Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Additional Records 5021
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Additional Records
1884-1936
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen (BRT)
5021
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Records of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, including draft manuscript of a History of the BRT, Convention proceedings, an insurance certificate and a condensed history compiled by S.G. Fleisher.
5984180
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 22, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Scope and Contents
Includes folders in chronological order beginning with 1884. Appears to be draft mss of book - "History of the BRT"; 1st Convention Proceedings, 1884, "oldest insurance certificate"; "condensed history, 1885-1936" compiled by S.G. Fleisher
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5102: Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records 5149: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Records 5149 MB: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Memorabilia 5149 P: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photographs 5348: W.P. Kennedy as President of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen against the Long Island Railroad Company Court Documents 5446: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Ledger 5612: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Moosic Tunnel Lodge no.93 Meeting Minutes 5623: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Legislative Board of New York Files 5631: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific Railroad General Committee File 5647: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Joppa Lodge (Toledo, OH) Minute Books 5894: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Additional Railroad Booklets 6268 P: Joint Committee of Adjustment for the Rock Island System's Order of Railway Conductors and Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photograph 6312 P: Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photographs 6312 PUBS: Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Publications 6312m: Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Annual Report of the Legislative Board 6405 PUBS: William Sharp Collection of The Railroad Trainmen's Journal 6480 MB: Paul Berger Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Memorabilia
Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions; Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen
5984180
- Condensed History Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, 1885-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- B.R.T. History, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- History of B.R.T. Organizational Plan for the Book (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Second Biennial Convention--Journal, Vol. XII, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- (Settlement of Great Northern Strike--Journal, Vol. XI, p. ), 1895 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- (Resume of Brotherhood History, Journal, Vol. X, p. 1040-45), 1893 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- (Special Convention, Galesburg, Illinois, October, October 5-16, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- (1890 BRT) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- (Chapter VIII Sixth Annual convention), 1889 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1888 Brotherhood of the Brakemen (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Testimony of A.F. Whitney, President, Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, on War Mobilization Bill S.607 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1886 (Third Convention, San Antonio, Texas, October 18-27, 1886) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Foreword, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Second Annual Convention-Brotherhood of Railroad Brakemen-Oct 20, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- (Journal, Vol XI), 1877-1884 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Chapter IX Reconstruction, 1895-1899 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Chapter VII A.R.U. + Aftermath, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Chapter VI Panic, Strikes, Legislation, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Chapter V Progress, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Chapter IV Formative Years 1884-1888 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Chapter III Oneonta (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Chapter I Inception (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Chapter 2 Eugene v. Debs, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- The Home Corres. + Data - (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Publications Railroad Journal (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Dining Car Stewards, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Oldest Insurance Certificate, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Proceedings of the First Annual Convention 1884 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Kate Shelley, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Chapter XIII 8 hr. day, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Chapter XII 1909-1915 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Chapter XI Employers' Liability (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Chapter X Groentreth Century (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Chapter Joint Concerted Wage Movement, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Canadian Transportation - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Chapter Second Quadrennial Convention, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Celebration of Victory in '37 Wage Strike, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Wrangling over Wages and R.A. Edwards, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Chapter Depression and Bank Collapse, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Chapter General Chairman & Buenos Aires, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Chapter The Ten Percent Wage Deduction, 1934-1944 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- The Panic - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- History of the Brotherhood, 1932-1944 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Wage Controversy Canada 1931 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- 1930 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 45)
- 1929 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 46)
- 1928 - Carbons, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- 1927 Carbons, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- 1926 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 49)
- 1925 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 50)
- 1924 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 51)
- 1923 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 52)
- 1922 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 53)
- 1921 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Year of 1920 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- 1919 - Carbon (Box 1, Folder 56)
- 1918 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 57)
- 1917 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 58)
- 1916 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 59)
- 1915 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 60)
- 1914 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 61)
- 1913 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 62)
- 1912 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 63)
- 1911 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 64)
- 1910 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 65)
- 1909 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 66)
- 1909 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 67)
- 1908 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 68)
- 1907 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 69)
- 1906 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 70)
- 1905 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 71)
- 1904 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 72)
- 1903 - Calories (Box 1, Folder 73)
- 1902 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 74)
- 1901 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 75)
- 1900 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 76)
- 1899 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 77)
- 1898 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 78)
- 1897 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 79)
- 1896 - Carbons (Box 1, Folder 80)